<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Your awesome title</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 19:38:23 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 19:38:23 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 19:35:21 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/09/06/welcome-to-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/09/06/welcome-to-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Trickle Down</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trickle-down Economics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In economics history of U.S, there is once upon a time when Reaganomics were popular in the 1980s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before Reagon came to power, there is high unemployment and persistently high inflation. In other word, it was called stagnation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It advocates cuts to the tax, which goes to the weathy and celebrities who are at the top of the pyrimaid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loneliness in Collectivism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;590&quot; height=&quot;330&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nx2iLOvP0rM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It reminds of the death of Avicii, who was a famous Nodiac music star. It happened on his trip to Oman,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All his notes were in happy mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These who are close to him are even more surprised than the fans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hate the labelling, it attaches atigma, ignores the heterogenity of the individual and often is the source of bias.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A little happiness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little happiness is originated from the American literature while introduced to East Asia by Japanese Novelist Murakami Haruki, to denote the tender moments in life which shall be recognized and cherished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little bit sweet or kind from people can make me feel blessed and grateful for the whole day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As Sherlock Holmes pointed out, When you have eliminated the impossible, whatever remains, however improbable, must be the truth. 
 						– A. Conan Doyle, The Sign of Four&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Establishing a close relationship with others is hard after becoming an adult.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 03:32:24 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/09/06/trickle-down.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/09/06/trickle-down.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Love, Lust and Loneliness</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cruel Truth about Love&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never did I have think about being detached to my parents in such a short time, when all things are going smooth and quite well by normal standard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when I stand by on the other side of the globe, hearing the quarrelling thousands miles away, even it’s a sunny Saturday, all the days have become grey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time, they did not have the chance to blow my mind, I clicked on the close button and quit Wechat as soon as possible, my dad might be experiencing one of the most challenging transition in his lifehood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big year for him has turned my mom into a part-time worker, with much more freedom in the name time for personal use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth, however, I saw is exactly the opposite. She does have an increasing amount of time as the Mom-and-Papa ‘s store has shut down,  but the time allocated for herself is so limited that I don’t even know how she can balance the inner self both emotionally and intellectually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As my dad is someone who just have no idea on how “the way of the world” works, my mom has to take on the role as the public relationship agent for him, and for the whole family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often times, in some occasion when my dad need to schemooze alone, confilcts are generated. The “Mianzi” maintained by my mom is exhausted easily by my dad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ineffective communication and the unwillingness to reveal some rules or social norms frequently lead them to a within-family arguments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Culturally speaking, this kind of overwhelmed lifestyle mostly come from the dominant power of father in Asian society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It all starts with boredom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In China, I cannot imagine how many men are still soaking in the illusion of traditional family expectation and roles arrangement,the burdensome housekeeping and babysitting responsibilities are not the only causes that frustrate women, moreover, I should say, fatigue resulted from the emotional labor they devoted and inability to make any changes in the power dynamics structure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, I have to be frank, typical idea that the boredom comes from too much freetime available, in fact，things are not that simple as it was talked about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loneliness in Collectivism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;590&quot; height=&quot;330&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nx2iLOvP0rM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It reminds of the death of Avicii, who was a famous Nodiac music star. It happened on his trip to Oman,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All his notes were in happy mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These who are close to him are even more surprised than the fans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hate the labelling, it attaches atigma, ignores the heterogenity of the individual and often is the source of bias.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A little happiness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/64.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Notre Dame Cathedral fire&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little happiness is originated from the American literature while introduced to East Asia by Japanese Novelist Murakami Haruki, to denote the tender moments in life which shall be recognized and cherished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little bit sweet or kind from people can make me feel blessed and grateful for the whole day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, it is in the second culture do we find ourselves, who we are and why we try so hard: to heal a wound in the childhood, to earn the sense of belonging, or what’s more, to gain all the needs which satisfy themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is the tiny kind that makes the life looks better than it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are normal people, normal to live and normal to die, always have no say for most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bosses buy our time by using their power and money, we nod our head to earn a living. The reverse of attitudes and behaviors are also a crucial reason why we feel quite lonely in these days, we are given the chance to say No, but based on the optimization strategy, keeping quiet is always a better choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Egregious things never takes a dominant role in life, for individuals fall within the three-sigma range, what affect them most is how they treat their normal life, the working time and spare time, their food and sleep, also a tiny bit risky event may cross over a while in their life-course, maybe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will loneliness lead to more loneliness? Yes, just the same as “matthew effect”. Rich people always get richer and the poor tends to stay in the lower stack of the society and sometimes siginificant event will drag them into the abyss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be fair, by using a psychoanalysis for myself, I am the one who would priortize emotional safety over social opportunity. Like a lollipop, if it looks too fancy, then I would be too eager to want it so that I abandoned it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In this consumer society, what cannot be bought?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are still many stuff, faith, love, trust and the willingness to make changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can ignore the existence of these invisible concepts, while credit is consist of trust, marriage is made from love and material exchange, and the urge to step out of the comfort zone contributes to the progress around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 21:32:24 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/08/30/Lust-and-Loneliness.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/08/30/Lust-and-Loneliness.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cost of Switching from divergent tasks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/post_multi.png&quot; alt=&quot;Multitasking&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We are drowning in information and starving for knowledge.
                                        –Rutherford D. Roger&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the book &lt;em&gt;elements of statistical learning&lt;/em&gt;, the author shared with us his experience in analyzing data, stating that statistician’s job is to make sense of it all: to extract important patterns and trends, and understand “what the data says.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, for a fresh green-hand who just enters the industry field, things can be challenging sometimes as we may never easily start from the cleaned, organized data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are checking the messy data, it just implies welcome to the real world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything from single details to the big picture of life are composed of learning problems that we consider can be roughly categorized as either &lt;em&gt;supervised&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;unsupervised&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-individual-does-multi-tasking-physically&quot;&gt;How individual does multi-tasking physically?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the neuroscience studies, we know prefrontal cortex of the brain begins working anytime you need to pay attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;design-working-log&quot;&gt;Design working log&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I learned from Diana, is try to design the working log of myself. Sometimes, I feel that I have no &lt;strong&gt;me time&lt;/strong&gt; left for myself or I feel exhausted&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 06:36:24 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/06/29/Cost-switching.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/06/29/Cost-switching.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Two separated world</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/post_notre_dame_cathedral.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Notre Dame Cathedral fire&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Plato developed a two layer view of reality, the world of Becoming and the world of Being. &lt;br /&gt;
         — symposium, Plato&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world of Becoming is the physical world we percieve through our senses. This world is always in movement, always changing. The world of Being is the world of forms, or ideas. It is absolute, independent, and transcendent. It never changes and yet causes the essential nature of things we percieve in the world of Becoming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Massive blaze encompasses the Notre Dame Cathedral, which is not only a landmark of Paris,  also an icon of Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shock and quietness engulf all the people, real fears spread among the public, media delineate this event as a devastating disaster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roof has collapsed on such a so-called historical day, isn’t it ironic? you may able to call it an absolute tragedy for these families who have overseen the rise and falls besides the once-romantic Seine bank in Paris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The grief, or you can called it the sense of feeling lost your beloved stuff, friends, appeared again for millions of parisians.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you watch closely to everyone’s life, you will find there will always be certain degree of shades. There is no doubt, some of us are the lucky dogs among all creatures of God, fortune or wealth, good education or luxury commodities, it always seems to be easy and convenient. However, for those diagnosed with rare disease, are they doomed to suffer from the date of birth? I am completely discouraged by the world, and still I am a person trying to enjoy all the privilege brought to me by my family, abuse resources I have available with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;No hope forever,  No &lt;em&gt;orietur&lt;/em&gt;.
Science and patience,
The torment is sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the pursuit of knowledge per se cannot change the situation, what should I insist? It is almost impossible for one to keep up with the latest information every moment, it’s often exhausting and tiring, sometimes disappointing, but there is also miracle that exists always.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the darkest days, tears and down hours, these will in the final be faded away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are limited time allocated for families, science and society. No wonder, why after carrying on the responsibility to maintain the role of breadwinner in family, more care and attention are paid for the internal mechanism of the tiny cell’s interest instead of the stars on the beautify sky, not necessarily cosmology, but one more important mission for one him/herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Platonic instinct to &lt;strong&gt;seek a higher principle&lt;/strong&gt; is rooted in my mind, perhaps that is the reason why I can accept my normal good-looking and just above C+ dressing style, as for me, now the &lt;strong&gt;beauty as capital&lt;/strong&gt; still cannot be prioritized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am no copy of anyone, unique and should be cherished, not being able to fulfill eternity, just live in the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 08:32:24 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/04/23/Two-separated-world.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/04/23/Two-separated-world.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nothing Forever</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/post_notre_dame_cathedral.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Notre Dame Cathedral fire&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;O my eternal soul,
&lt;br /&gt;
 Hold fast to desire&lt;br /&gt;
In spite of the night&lt;br /&gt;
 And the day on fire.&lt;br /&gt;
And Spring brought me the frightening laugh of the idiot.&lt;br /&gt;
	         — A Season in Hell &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.poets.org/node/44836&quot;&gt;Arthur Rimbaud&lt;/a&gt;, 1854 - 1891&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Massive blaze encompasses the Notre Dame Cathedral, which is not only a landmark of Paris,  also an icon of Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shock and quietness engulf all the people, real fears spread among the public, media delineate this event as a devastating disaster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roof has collapsed on such a so-called historical day, isn’t it ironic? you may able to call it an absolute tragedy for these families who have overseen the rise and falls besides the once-romantic Seine bank in Paris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The grief, or you can called it the sense of feeling lost your beloved stuff, friends, appeared again for millions of parisians.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you watch closely to everyone’s life, you will find there will always be certain degree of shades. There is no doubt, some of us are the lucky dogs among all creatures of God, fortune or wealth, good education or luxury commodities, it always seems to be easy and convenient. However, for those diagnosed with rare disease, are they doomed to suffer from the date of birth? I am completely discouraged by the world, and still I am a person trying to enjoy all the privilege brought to me by my family, abuse resources I have available with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;No hope forever,  No &lt;em&gt;orietur&lt;/em&gt;.
Science and patience,
The torment is sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the pursuit of knowledge per se cannot change the situation, what should I insist? It is almost impossible for one to keep up with the latest information every moment, it’s often exhausting and tiring, sometimes disappointing, but there is also miracle that exists always.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the darkest days, tears and down hours, these will in the final be faded away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are limited time allocated for families, science and society. No wonder, why after carrying on the responsibility to maintain the role of breadwinner in family, more care and attention are paid for the internal mechanism of the tiny cell’s interest instead of the stars on the beautify sky, not necessarily cosmology, but one more important mission for one him/herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Platonic instinct to &lt;strong&gt;seek a higher principle&lt;/strong&gt; is rooted in my mind, perhaps that is the reason why I can accept my normal good-looking and just above C+ dressing style, as for me, now the &lt;strong&gt;beauty as capital&lt;/strong&gt; still cannot be prioritized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am no copy of anyone, unique and should be cherished, not being able to fulfill eternity, just live in the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 08:32:24 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/04/15/Nothing-Forever.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/04/15/Nothing-Forever.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Latent Variable Tutorial</title>
        <description>&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#lec-1--introduction&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-lec-1--introduction&quot;&gt;Lec 1  Introduction&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#motivating-examples&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-motivating-examples&quot;&gt;Motivating Examples&lt;/a&gt;        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#models&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-models&quot;&gt;Models&lt;/a&gt;            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#unsupervised-learning&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-unsupervised-learning&quot;&gt;Unsupervised Learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#software-usage&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-software-usage&quot;&gt;Software Usage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#lec2-fundamental-ideas-of-measurement&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-lec2-fundamental-ideas-of-measurement&quot;&gt;Lec2 Fundamental Ideas of Measurement&lt;/a&gt;        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#steps-for-creating-measurement&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-steps-for-creating-measurement&quot;&gt;Steps for creating measurement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1-construct-latent-variable-definition-and-content-domain&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-1-construct-latent-variable-definition-and-content-domain&quot;&gt;1. Construct latent variable definition and content domain&lt;/a&gt;            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#deiphi-method&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-deiphi-method&quot;&gt;Deiphi Method&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#levels-of-measurement&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-levels-of-measurement&quot;&gt;Levels of Measurement&lt;/a&gt;                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#nominal-data&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-nominal-data&quot;&gt;Nominal Data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ordinal-data&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-ordinal-data&quot;&gt;Ordinal Data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#interval-data&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-interval-data&quot;&gt;Interval Data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ratio-data&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-ratio-data&quot;&gt;Ratio Data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#2-generating-and-judging-measurement-items&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-2-generating-and-judging-measurement-items&quot;&gt;2. Generating and judging measurement items&lt;/a&gt;            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#criteria&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-criteria&quot;&gt;Criteria&lt;/a&gt;                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#reliability&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-reliability&quot;&gt;Reliability&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#validity&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-validity&quot;&gt;Validity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#dimensionality&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-dimensionality&quot;&gt;Dimensionality&lt;/a&gt;                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#formative-vs-reflective-measurement&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-formative-vs-reflective-measurement&quot;&gt;Formative vs Reflective measurement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#cronbachs-alpha&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-cronbachs-alpha&quot;&gt;Cronbach’s alpha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#lec-3-factor-analysis-part-i&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-lec-3-factor-analysis-part-i&quot;&gt;Lec 3 Factor Analysis Part I&lt;/a&gt;        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#general-theory-and-exploratory-factor-analysis&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-general-theory-and-exploratory-factor-analysis&quot;&gt;General Theory and Exploratory Factor Analysis&lt;/a&gt;            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#factor-analysis-model&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-factor-analysis-model&quot;&gt;Factor Analysis Model&lt;/a&gt;                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#commonly-used-cut-offs-indicating-good-fit-of-the-model&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-commonly-used-cut-offs-indicating-good-fit-of-the-model&quot;&gt;Commonly used cut-offs indicating “good fit” of the model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#model-comparison&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-model-comparison&quot;&gt;Model comparison&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#exploratory-factor-analysis&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-exploratory-factor-analysis&quot;&gt;Exploratory Factor Analysis&lt;/a&gt;            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#steps-in-an-efa&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-steps-in-an-efa&quot;&gt;Steps in an EFA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#rotation&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-rotation&quot;&gt;Rotation&lt;/a&gt;                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#types-of-rotations&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-types-of-rotations&quot;&gt;Types of Rotations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#two-examples-for-efa&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-two-examples-for-efa&quot;&gt;Two Examples for EFA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#lec-4-factor-analysis-part-ii&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-lec-4-factor-analysis-part-ii&quot;&gt;Lec 4 Factor Analysis Part II&lt;/a&gt;        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#confirmatory-factor-analysis&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-confirmatory-factor-analysis&quot;&gt;Confirmatory Factor Analysis&lt;/a&gt;            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#specify-a-cfa-in-mplus&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-specify-a-cfa-in-mplus&quot;&gt;Specify a CFA in MPLUS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#degrees-of-freedom&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-degrees-of-freedom&quot;&gt;Degrees of Freedom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#standardized-and-unstandardized&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-standardized-and-unstandardized&quot;&gt;Standardized and Unstandardized&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#model-comparison-1&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-model-comparison-1&quot;&gt;Model Comparison&lt;/a&gt;                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#nested-model&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-nested-model&quot;&gt;Nested model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#modification-indices&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-modification-indices&quot;&gt;Modification Indices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#lec-5-factor-analysis-part-iii&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-lec-5-factor-analysis-part-iii&quot;&gt;Lec 5 Factor Analysis Part III&lt;/a&gt;        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#item-response-theory&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-item-response-theory&quot;&gt;Item Response Theory&lt;/a&gt;            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#discrimination&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-discrimination&quot;&gt;Discrimination&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#severity&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-severity&quot;&gt;Severity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#measurement-invariance-using-mimic&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-measurement-invariance-using-mimic&quot;&gt;Measurement invariance using MIMIC&lt;/a&gt;            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#differential-item-functioning&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-differential-item-functioning&quot;&gt;Differential item Functioning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#bifactor-modeling&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-bifactor-modeling&quot;&gt;Bifactor modeling&lt;/a&gt;            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#second-order-factor-model&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-second-order-factor-model&quot;&gt;Second-order factor model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#lec-6-latent-class-analysis&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-lec-6-latent-class-analysis&quot;&gt;Lec 6 Latent Class Analysis&lt;/a&gt;        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#item--response-theory-catrgorical-latent-variable-modeling&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-item--response-theory-catrgorical-latent-variable-modeling&quot;&gt;Item  Response Theory: Catrgorical latent variable modeling&lt;/a&gt;            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#lca-general-theory&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-lca-general-theory&quot;&gt;LCA general Theory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#model&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-model&quot;&gt;Model&lt;/a&gt;                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#item-difficulty&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-item-difficulty&quot;&gt;Item Difficulty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#item-discrimination&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-item-discrimination&quot;&gt;Item Discrimination&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#pseudo-change-parameter&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-pseudo-change-parameter&quot;&gt;Pseudo-change parameter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#lec-8-structural-equation-model-i&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-lec-8-structural-equation-model-i&quot;&gt;Lec 8 Structural Equation Model I&lt;/a&gt;        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#origin-of-structural-equation-model&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-origin-of-structural-equation-model&quot;&gt;Origin of Structural Equation model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#lec-10-sem&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-lec-10-sem&quot;&gt;Lec 10 SEM&lt;/a&gt;        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#resources&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#appendix&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-appendix&quot;&gt;Appendix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/mathjax/2.7.5/MathJax.js?config=TeX-MML-AM_CHTML&quot; async=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;lec-1--introduction&quot;&gt;Lec 1  Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;motivating-examples&quot;&gt;Motivating Examples&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You are a sociologist who has collected a social network and various attributes about each person. You use a latent variable model to discover the underlying communities in this population and to characterize the kinds of people that participate in each. The discovered communities help you understand &lt;strong&gt;the structure of the network&lt;/strong&gt; and help predict “missing” edges, such as people who know each other but are not yet linked or people who would enjoy meeting each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&amp;quot;/img/Box's loop.png&amp;quot;&quot; alt=&quot;Box's loop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;George Box and collaborators proposed a Box’s loop in the 1960s, by adopting scientific method, Box tried to understand nature by iterative experimental design, data collection, model formulation, and model criticism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;models&quot;&gt;Models&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Latent Varible Measurement and Structural Equation modelling&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Latent Varible Measurement&lt;/strong&gt; : statistical models are used to discover and describe the way that observed variables are related to underlying variables.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Structural Equation Modelling&lt;/strong&gt;: Statistical and graphical modelling framework used to evaluate the presumed &lt;u&gt;causal relationships&lt;/u&gt;(direct or indirect) among several variables(possibly latent).&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Latent Variable&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Not observed or measured directly;&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;measured with error or can only be measured with error;&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Used for representing a “True” variable which is measured with error, or a single conceptual variable, or a construct which is a summarization of a complex concept.&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;table&gt;
              &lt;thead&gt;
                &lt;tr&gt;
                  &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
                  &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Latent is &lt;em&gt;Continuous&lt;/em&gt;- f     Latent is &lt;em&gt;Categorical&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
                  &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;/tr&gt;
              &lt;/thead&gt;
              &lt;tbody&gt;
                &lt;tr&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;Observed Continuous &lt;strong&gt;Y&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Factor Analysis                     Finite  Mixture model&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;/tr&gt;
                &lt;tr&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Latent Mixture model&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;/tr&gt;
                &lt;tr&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Latent profile analysis&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;/tr&gt;
                &lt;tr&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt;Observed Catrgorical &lt;strong&gt;U&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Latent Trait model              &lt;strong&gt;“Latent class&lt;/strong&gt;” Analysis&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;/tr&gt;
                &lt;tr&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Item Response Theory&lt;/td&gt;
                  &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;/tr&gt;
              &lt;/tbody&gt;
            &lt;/table&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;Factor Analysis of categorical observed variables&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Latent variable measurement&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supervised learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Supervised learning methods are such as regression and classification: In that setting we observe both a set of features X1, X2, . . . , Xp for each object, as well as a response or outcome variable Y . The goal is then to predict Y using X1, X2, . . . , Xp.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;

    &lt;h5 id=&quot;unsupervised-learning&quot;&gt;Unsupervised Learning&lt;/h5&gt;

    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Unsupervised learning here, we where observe only the features X1, X2, . . . , Xp. We are not interested in prediction, because we do not have an associated response variable Y .&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;principal components analysis&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, a tool used for data visualization or data pre-processing before supervised
techniques are applied, and&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Clustering&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, a broad class of methods for discovering unknown subgroups in data.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;software-usage&quot;&gt;Software Usage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;R: &lt;a href=&quot;http://lavaan.ugent.be/tutorial/index.html&quot;&gt;Lavaan Package&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mplus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SAS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lec2-fundamental-ideas-of-measurement&quot;&gt;Lec2 Fundamental Ideas of Measurement&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;steps-for-creating-measurement&quot;&gt;Steps for creating measurement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Construct latent variable definition and content domain&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Generating and judging measurement items&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Designing and conducting studies to develop and refine scale&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finalizing the scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-construct-latent-variable-definition-and-content-domain&quot;&gt;1. Construct latent variable definition and content domain&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;deiphi-method&quot;&gt;Deiphi Method&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dephi method is a systematic, iterative method that relies on a  group of usually anonymous experts in order to get the collective intelligence or “wisodm of clouds”, then for generating/trimming measurement item sets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;levels-of-measurement&quot;&gt;Levels of Measurement&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Statisticians commonly distinguish &lt;u&gt;four types or levels of measurement&lt;/u&gt;, and the same terms can refer to data measured at each level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The levels of measurement differ both in terms of the meaning of the numbers used in the measurement system and in the types of statistical procedures that can be applied appropriately to data measured at each level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;nominal-data&quot;&gt;Nominal Data&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the name implies, the numbers function as a &lt;em&gt;name&lt;/em&gt; or label and do not have numeric meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When data can take on only two values, as in the male/female example, it can also be called &lt;em&gt;binary&lt;/em&gt; data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;ordinal-data&quot;&gt;Ordinal Data&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ordinal data&lt;/em&gt; refers to data that has some meaningful &lt;em&gt;order&lt;/em&gt;, so that higher values represent more of some characteristic than lower values. However, there is no metric analogous to a ruler or scale to quantify how great the distance between categories is, nor is it possible to determine whether the difference between first- and second-degree burns is the same as the difference between second- and third-degree burns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;interval-data&quot;&gt;Interval Data&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interval&lt;/em&gt; data has a meaningful order and has the quality of &lt;em&gt;equal intervals&lt;/em&gt; between measurements, representing equal changes in the quantity of whatever is being measured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, it is appropriate to calculate the median (central value) of ordinal data but not the mean because it assumes equal intervals and requires division, which requires ratio-level data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;ratio-data&quot;&gt;Ratio Data&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ratio&lt;/em&gt; data has all the qualities of interval data (meaningful order, equal intervals) and a natural zero point. Many physical measurements are ratio data: for instance, height, weight, and age all qualify. So does income: you can certainly earn 0 dollars in a year or have 0 dollars in your bank account, and this signifies an absence of money. With ratio-level data, it is appropriate to multiply and divide as well as add and subtract; it makes sense to say that someone with &lt;em&gt;100 has twice as much money as someone with 50&lt;/em&gt; or that a person who is 30 years old is 3 times as old as someone who is 10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-generating-and-judging-measurement-items&quot;&gt;2. Generating and judging measurement items&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assessment of the quality of a measurement instrument, we may have several criteria for evaluation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;criteria&quot;&gt;Criteria&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;Reliability&lt;/u&gt;: Observation and operations are repeateable or reproducible&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;Validity&lt;/u&gt;: The observations selected to represent or indicate a concept infact do so&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consistentency&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clarity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consensus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;reliability&quot;&gt;Reliability&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Definition: The degree to which the instrument is free from error&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internal Consistency&lt;/strong&gt;:  precision of a scale, based on homogeneity (intercorrelations) of the scale’s items at one point in time;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reproducibility&lt;/strong&gt;: stability of an instrument over time (test -retest) and or across raters( inter-rater agreement)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;validity&quot;&gt;Validity&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Definition: The degree to which the instrument measures what it purports to measure&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content validity&lt;/strong&gt;: evidence that the content domain is appropriate to its  intended use, sometimes called face or qualitative validity.&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;p&gt;For example, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Depression_(mood)&quot;&gt;depression&lt;/a&gt; scale may lack content validity if it only assesses the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Affective&quot;&gt;affective&lt;/a&gt; dimension of depression but fails to take into account the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Behavioral&quot;&gt;behavioral&lt;/a&gt; dimension.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Construct validity&lt;/strong&gt;: Consistent with hypothesized concepts;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Criterion validity&lt;/strong&gt;:  &lt;em&gt;Criterion-related validity&lt;/em&gt; usually includes any validity strategies that focus on the correlation of the test being validated with some well-respected outside measure(s) of the same objectives or specifications.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;For instance, if a group of testers were trying to develop a test for business English to be administered primarily in Japan and Korea, they might decide to administer their new test and the TOEIC® to a fairly large group of students and then calculate the degree of correlation between the two tests. If the correlation coefficient between the new test and the TOEIC turned out to be high, that would indicate that the new test was arranging the students along a continuum of proficiency levels very much like the TOEIC does – a result that could, in turn, be used to support the validity of the new test. Criterion-related validity of this sort is sometimes called &lt;em&gt;concurrent validity&lt;/em&gt; (because both tests are administered at about the same time).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;dimensionality&quot;&gt;Dimensionality&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many continuous latent variables are being measured by the items;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;formative-vs-reflective-measurement&quot;&gt;Formative vs Reflective measurement&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-tbIyncnA95s/UWUqtEBPf4I/AAAAAAAAD88/fx-chNHSILY/s1600/%E6%8A%95%E5%BD%B1%E7%89%872.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Formative Indicator&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: An observable, reflective indicator can be seen as a function of a latent variable (or construct), whereby changes in the latent variable are reflected in changes in observable indicators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Constructive Indicator&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: in formative cases, changes in indicators determine changes in the value of the latent variable (construct).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Scale&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; : scale formed from items assumed to be reflective measures of the latent variable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Index&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;:  an index is formed from a set of items assumed to be formative of the latent variable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Scale&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Index&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;reflective measures&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;formative measures&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;“reflected” by the latent construct&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;items drive the total score&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In scaling, scores on items in the scale are theoretically driven by the latent construct; that is, they are “reflected” by the latent construct.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;With an index, scores on items (indicators) drive the total score of the index; that is, the items/indicators “form” the constructed index score.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parallel Analysis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;cronbachs-alpha&quot;&gt;Cronbach’s alpha&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally, $\alpha​$ is a measure if how correlated the items in the scale are with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$\alpha​$ is measure of the lower bound for the reliability of a simple sum or average scale under the important assumption that the items are &lt;strong&gt;reflective&lt;/strong&gt; and are &lt;strong&gt;unidimensional&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally $\alpha$ increases as the number of items increases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-SAS&quot;&gt;Proc corr data = a alpha nomiss;
Var c22 c4;
run;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$\alpha​$ = Intraclass correlation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lec-3-factor-analysis-part-i&quot;&gt;Lec 3 Factor Analysis Part I&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;general-theory-and-exploratory-factor-analysis&quot;&gt;General Theory and Exploratory Factor Analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;factor-analysis-model&quot;&gt;Factor Analysis Model&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All models are wrong, but some are useful. — Geogre Box&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;y = v + \beta f + e&lt;/script&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;$f$: often called “common factors”;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;$v$: intercept, for EFA, v = 0, and for CFA often directly model v&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Var(e) = $\Theta$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;commonly-used-cut-offs-indicating-good-fit-of-the-model&quot;&gt;Commonly used cut-offs indicating “good fit” of the model&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Fit statistic&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Values indicating “good fit”&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;CFI&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&amp;gt;0.90/0.95&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;TLI&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&amp;gt;0.90/0.95&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;RMSEA&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&amp;lt;0.08(adequate fit) | &amp;lt; 0.05/0.06(good fit)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;SRMR&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&amp;lt;0.07&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;WRMR&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&amp;lt;1.0&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NOTE:  The more complicated the model is, the better the fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;model-comparison&quot;&gt;Model comparison&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goal&lt;/strong&gt;: More pasimonous model is just as good as the more complicated model.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two ways:
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chi-square&lt;/strong&gt; difference test for nested models;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;information criterion: &lt;strong&gt;AIC, BIC&lt;/strong&gt; for non-nested models(or nested models)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exploratory-factor-analysis&quot;&gt;Exploratory Factor Analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;steps-in-an-efa&quot;&gt;Steps in an EFA&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;performing an eigenvalue analysis to get an estimate(or range) for the number of underlying dimensions;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimate the parameters in the models with different number of factors;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Put factor loadings: side by side, from the different models;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Common to use the value &lt;strong&gt;greater&lt;/strong&gt; than &lt;strong&gt;0.4&lt;/strong&gt; or 0.3 for factor loadings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rerun all the steps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;rotation&quot;&gt;Rotation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In EFA, because we have no restricitions on variance, there is more than one estimate for variance that can give us the same model covariance matrix model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intuitively, this shows two different estimates can fit the data exactly the same way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rotation is the technique we use to specify which variance we want to estimate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;types-of-rotations&quot;&gt;Types of Rotations&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically rotation methods aim to give the estimated loadings as close to &lt;strong&gt;simple structure&lt;/strong&gt; as possible. “&lt;strong&gt;simple structure&lt;/strong&gt;” means that each observed variable loads on one and only one factor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oblique Rotation&lt;/strong&gt;: commonly used for since we often hypothesize our latent variables of interest to be &lt;strong&gt;correlated with one another.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-sql highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;Default&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;MPLUS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;GEOMIN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;other&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;method&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;called&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;PROMAX&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Orthogonal Rotation&lt;/strong&gt; :it is desirable to identify factors that are as independent from one another as possible, often not possible to find “simple structure” with orthogonal rotation.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-sql highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;VARIMAX&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;default&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;h5 id=&quot;two-examples-for-efa&quot;&gt;Two Examples for EFA&lt;/h5&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Nicotine Example&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-SAS&quot;&gt;TITLE: this is an example of an exploratory factor analysis with continuous factor indicators
DATA: FILE IS ex4.1a.dat;
VARIABLE: NAMES ARE y1-y12;
ANALYSIS: TYPE = EFA 1 4;
OUTPUT: MODINDICES;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

        &lt;p&gt;By specifying &lt;em&gt;TYPE=EFA&lt;/em&gt;, an exploratory factor analysis will be carried out. The numbers following EFA give the &lt;strong&gt;lower&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;upper limits&lt;/strong&gt; on the number of factors to be extracted, here 4 factors will be extracted, if you want an exact 2 factor model, then input:&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-SAS&quot;&gt;ANALYSIS: TYPE = EFA 2 2;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;

    &lt;hr /&gt;

    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;They &lt;strong&gt;calculated eigenvalues and assessed the amount of variability&lt;/strong&gt; explained by the 5 eigenvalues &lt;strong&gt;larger than one&lt;/strong&gt;. The first factor explained 43% of the variance with the second through fifth factor adding only 4%-7% to the variance explained by the first factor.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;They created a &lt;strong&gt;scree-plot&lt;/strong&gt;, which showed a break between the steep slope of the first factor and a &lt;strong&gt;gradual trailing&lt;/strong&gt; of the remaining factor.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Measuring complicated Grief&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-SAS&quot;&gt;TITLE: this is an example of an exploratory factor analysis with categorical factor indicators
DATA: FILE IS ex4.2.dat;
VARIABLE: NAMES ARE u1-u12;
CATEGORICAL ARE u1-u12;
ANALYSIS: TYPE = EFA 1 4;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

        &lt;p&gt;factor indicators are &lt;em&gt;binary or ordered categorical (ordinal)&lt;/em&gt; variables instead of
continuous variables&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lec-4-factor-analysis-part-ii&quot;&gt;Lec 4 Factor Analysis Part II&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;confirmatory-factor-analysis&quot;&gt;Confirmatory Factor Analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;EFA: we need to specify how many factors we want to fit.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CFA: we have a set of observed items and in addition to specifying how many factors, we also need to specify &lt;u&gt;which of the factors are related to which&lt;/u&gt; of the items and whether we want to allow any of the &lt;u&gt;measurement errors to be correlated&lt;/u&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;specify-a-cfa-in-mplus&quot;&gt;Specify a CFA in MPLUS&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;degrees-of-freedom&quot;&gt;Degrees of Freedom&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In EFA  d.f. =   $\frac{P * (p+1)}{2} - p * q - p + \frac{q *(q-1)}{2}​$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In CFA d.f. =  $\frac{P * (p+1)}{2} - No. of$ parameters est.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;standardized-and-unstandardized&quot;&gt;Standardized and Unstandardized&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standardized&lt;/strong&gt;: fix the variance to be 1.0.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unstandardized:&lt;/strong&gt; fix one factor loadings to be 1.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of time, &lt;em&gt;STDYX&lt;/em&gt; is used, while for including dichotomous X, we often use STDY for meaningful interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;model-comparison-1&quot;&gt;Model Comparison&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;nested-model&quot;&gt;Nested model&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a model $M_1$ exist, $M_2$ imposes some restrictions on the parameter of $M_1$, then we say that $M_2$ is nested within  $M_1$.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When models are nested,  we can always perform a chi-square difference test to compare them, the idea is to test whether the more restrictive model fits significantly worse than the original less restrictive model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$H_0: M_2$ (More restrictive model),  $H_1: M_1$ (Full model)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;modification-indices&quot;&gt;Modification Indices&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each path that has not been included in the model has an associated “&lt;strong&gt;modification index&lt;/strong&gt;”. A modification indices tells you how much the &lt;u&gt;overall chi-square test statistic would improve&lt;/u&gt; if that particular path was added to the model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Expected Parameter Change indices-expected value of the parameter if it is estimated&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Adding one new path will decrease the degrees of freedom by one. So, since the model without the path can be considered “nested” within the model with the path, we can perform a chi-squared test for whether the path is needed or not.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The modification index equals chi-square difference test with 1 degree of freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Since &lt;strong&gt;3.84&lt;/strong&gt; is 0.05 cut-off value for a chi-square with 1 degree of freedom, modification indices greater than 3.84 suggest that the path should be added at the p=.05 level.
*&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lec-5-factor-analysis-part-iii&quot;&gt;Lec 5 Factor Analysis Part III&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-response-theory&quot;&gt;Item Response Theory&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;IRT model is developed from Education Testing field, to discriminate people along an underlying trait.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;IRT is a special CFA model with o&lt;u&gt;ne factor for dichotomous or ordered categorical outcomes&lt;/u&gt;, but uses direct estimation of probability of response functions rather than &lt;strong&gt;polychoric correlations&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;IRT uses logistic regression model structure, p logistic regressions, where unobserved continuous latent variable is the predictor for each regression.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Model&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two parameter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$logit(\pi_{ij}) = \beta_j(\theta_i - \alpha_j)​$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If fix all $\beta $ =1, then it is “&lt;strong&gt;Rasch Model&lt;/strong&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$\beta_j$: &lt;strong&gt;discrimination&lt;/strong&gt; parameter;   $\alpha_j$: &lt;strong&gt;severity&lt;/strong&gt; parameter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;discrimination&quot;&gt;Discrimination&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;item characteristic curve&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;severity&quot;&gt;Severity&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;measurement-invariance-using-mimic&quot;&gt;Measurement invariance using MIMIC&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One must assume that the numerical values under consideration are on the same measurement scale (Drasgow, 1984, 1987). That is, one must assumethat the test has “&lt;strong&gt;measurement invariance&lt;/strong&gt;” across groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;differential-item-functioning&quot;&gt;Differential item Functioning&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;configural invariance or factor form invariance — test whether the same item are associated with the same latent factor in each group&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Factor Loading or metric invariance (weak factorial invariance)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Intercept invariance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Residual invariance or strong invariance (strict factorial invariance)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Testing for Measurement invariance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MIMIC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;IRT-LR-DIF&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bifactor-modeling&quot;&gt;Bifactor modeling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an overall factor generally underlying every observed varaible. Also, there is domain specific factors of cognition, vitality, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also assumes that the relations among the general and domain specific factors are &lt;strong&gt;orthogonal&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;second-order-factor-model&quot;&gt;Second-order factor model&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lec-6-latent-class-analysis&quot;&gt;Lec 6 Latent Class Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item--response-theory-catrgorical-latent-variable-modeling&quot;&gt;Item  Response Theory: Catrgorical latent variable modeling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;lca-general-theory&quot;&gt;LCA general Theory&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Classic Test Theory (CTT)&lt;/strong&gt; is for use when you have &lt;u&gt;continuous&lt;/u&gt; variables, while you have &lt;u&gt;categorical( Dichotomous/Polytomous)&lt;/u&gt;, then you use &lt;strong&gt;Item Response Theory(IRT)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IRT is originated in the 1970s, and was originally called “Latent Trait models”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For both CTT and IRT, the observed variables are &lt;u&gt;**Continuous**&lt;/u&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;model&quot;&gt;Model&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Latent variable is hypothesized as &lt;u&gt;**Categorical**&lt;/u&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;item-difficulty&quot;&gt;Item Difficulty&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;How difficult the item is.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When conducting social science studies, sometimes people call it “item endorsability”. (Some items are more readily endorsed than others, you are more likely to say Yes or No on some items.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;item-discrimination&quot;&gt;Item Discrimination&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;How Strongly related the response on the item is on the undelying latent trait&lt;/u&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can regard it as how well the item discriminates among participants located at different points on the latent continuum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;pseudo-change-parameter&quot;&gt;Pseudo-change parameter&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The probability of choosing a correct answer by chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choice of K&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Predicting the class membership&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;High Morale soldier example&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Disordered eating behavioral example&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;LCA for diagnostic testing with no gold standard
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Estimates sensitivity and specificity&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Myocardinal infaction example&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;LCA for multiple source outcomes
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Colonoscopy screening example&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lec-8-structural-equation-model-i&quot;&gt;Lec 8 Structural Equation Model I&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;origin-of-structural-equation-model&quot;&gt;Origin of Structural Equation model&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;First:&lt;/em&gt;  Swell Wright, a geneticist in 1920s, attempted to solve simultaneous equations to disentangle genetic influences across generations (“path analysis”)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gained popularity in 1960, when Blalock, Duncan, and others introduced them to social science (e.g. status attainment processes)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The development of general linear models by &lt;u&gt;Joreskog and others&lt;/u&gt; in 1970s (“LISREL” models, i.e. linear structural relations)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difference between path analysis and structural equation modeling (SEM)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Path analysis is a special case of SEM&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Path analysis contains only observed variables and each&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;variable only has one indicator&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Path analysis assumes that all variables are measured without error&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SEM uses latent variables to account for measurement error&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Path analysis has a more restrictive set of assumptions than SEM (e.g. no correlation between the error terms)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the models that you will see in the literature are SEM rather than path analyses&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Structural Equation Model: often made up of two parts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;latent variable measurement model&lt;/strong&gt; (e.g. confirmatory factor&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;analysis, latent class analysis)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Path analysis model&lt;/strong&gt; (structural model) – model for assumed causal relationships&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lec-10-sem&quot;&gt;Lec 10 SEM&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.baylor.edu/rlatentvariable/&quot;&gt;Latent variable Analysis with R&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;A Step-By-Step Guide&lt;/em&gt;written by Beaujean&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;appendix&quot;&gt;Appendix&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MPlus&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-R highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;WITH&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;allow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;correlation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;

&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Errors are uncorrelated by default;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Factors are correlated by default;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 08:32:24 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/04/13/Latent-Varible-analysis-Tutorial.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/04/13/Latent-Varible-analysis-Tutorial.html</guid>
        
        <category>statistics</category>
        
        <category>latent variable</category>
        
        <category>Tutorial</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Python tutorial</title>
        <description>&lt;script src=&quot;https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/mathjax/2.7.5/MathJax.js?config=TeX-MML-AM_CHTML&quot; async=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All programming languages must be able to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;remember things,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;repeat things,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;communicate, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;make decisions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Functions are all about #2: &lt;strong&gt;repeating things&lt;/strong&gt;. Think of a function as a standalone mini-program: It takes some inputs, performs some operations, and generates an output. We define a function once, and we can execute the code define within a function as many times as we like – repeating all those lines of code with a single invocation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code we’ve written in Python have already employed functions – so far, we’ve defined a function named &lt;em&gt;main&lt;/em&gt; and invoked it to kick off the execution of a program.  But we’ll go way beyond that, defining many functions to do one small thing apiece, and putting them together into a larger program. Now that our programs are starting to get more robust and sophisticated, you’ll define functions beyond just main for pretty much everything you write. Not just in Python and not just in DS2000, but for all of your computer science/data science/programming going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Functions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Functions help us to organize our code. They save us from writing a big, long, ugly &lt;em&gt;main&lt;/em&gt;. A function is written once and then its code can be executed many times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Functions are short and concise. &lt;strong&gt;Keep this rule of thumb in mind:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;A  Function has one job.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We define a function to do its one little thing, and then we can execute that code many times, on all kinds of different inputs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We define functions because they are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Modular&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. We end up with many small, single-purpose functions, which we can then piece together into a larger program. It’s the same reason IKEA gives us a bunch of separate shelves that we assemble; it might be annoying, but it’s much easier than if we had to build the whole bookshelf from scratch ourselves.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Testable&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; We’ve written test cases for our Python programs in this class, which are great and useful. The drawback of what we’ve done so far, with everything in one big &lt;em&gt;main&lt;/em&gt;, is that &lt;u&gt;we need to provide input at the prompt&lt;/u&gt; and then &lt;strong&gt;eyeball the output&lt;/strong&gt; to make sure it all worked as expected. Functions enable us to test our code &lt;em&gt;programmatically&lt;/em&gt;  – instead of a human eyeball, it’s Python code that determines whether a function generated the correct output given an input. Much more reliable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reuseable&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; Once a function is defined, we can use it in many programs, sometimes with wildly different purposes. For example, Python provides a function that generates a random number, and I’ve used this function for programs that roll dice, deal a card from a deck, play a guessing game, play rock/scissors/paper, and basically any game of chance you can think of, because they’re my favorite programs to write. That one function has come in handy in tons of ways.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name, Parameters, Return Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A function is uniquely defined by three characteristics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Name (required)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; . Similar to a variable name, a function is named so we can refer to it elsewhere in the program.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Parameters (zero or more).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; The data types of its expected input(s). A parameter is a variable that is attached to the function. Because variables must be initialized before we can meaningful use them, a parameter is initialized by the function caller.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Return Type (zero or one).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; The data type of its expected output. A function performs some operation on its input, and returns the result to the function caller.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example of a simple function in Python, defined by the function writer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;divide&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;''' function: divide
        parameters: two numbers, x and y
        returns: a float, the result of dividing x / y
    '''&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;result&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;result&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s break it down to the important parts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name&lt;/strong&gt;: divide&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parameters&lt;/strong&gt;: two numbers, which could be floats or ints. The parameters are variables attached to the function, and they are named &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt;. You can see that &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt; are not initialized here in the function definition, but we know that we need them to be initialized so that we can use them – they’ll be given values by the function caller.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Return type&lt;/strong&gt;: a float. The function returns the result of &lt;em&gt;x / y&lt;/em&gt;, which is a float even if &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt; are both integers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few other things to notice here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is a block comment written just under the function name. It must be in block comments so that &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/2/library/pydoc.html&quot;&gt;pydoc&lt;/a&gt; will generate your function documentation correctly. For DS2000, we require both parameters and return type to be specified here, but including the name is optional (it’s just something I like to do so I can see them all together in IDLE’s green highlights).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The last line of the function is a &lt;strong&gt;return&lt;/strong&gt; statement. Return is a &lt;strong&gt;reserve word&lt;/strong&gt; in Python. Its job is to hand a value back to the caller. Once a return statement is executed, flow of control also returns to the caller. If any additional code were written here underneath the return statement, it would never be executed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A function is not required to return a value. &lt;u&gt;If it doesn’t return anything, we call it a “void function,”&lt;/u&gt; and we say that its return type is &lt;strong&gt;void.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;main&lt;/em&gt; functions we’ve defined in our programs so far don’t return anything; when the flow of control reaches the end of the function, the function just ends without explicitly requiring a return statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calling the function&lt;/strong&gt;. Here’s how it would look if I call the &lt;em&gt;divide&lt;/em&gt; function from somewhere inside my main function:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;What to notice here:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We had to know the &lt;em&gt;name, parameters&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;return type&lt;/em&gt; of this function in order to call it. That’s how we know the correct syntax for invoking it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We’ve named our variables here &lt;em&gt;a&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;b&lt;/em&gt; and initialized them to have the values 14 and 5. Therefore, 14 and 5 become the values associated with the function’s parameters &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt;. The values 14 and 5 are the &lt;strong&gt;arguments&lt;/strong&gt; to the divide function.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Because the function &lt;em&gt;divide&lt;/em&gt; returns a value, the function caller must save the value it returns. Otherwise, the result of dividing 14/5 would be lost. Here, we’re saving the result in a variable, but we could also print it out, or use it as input to another function… but we can’t ignore it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flow of Control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without functions, a basic little Python code snippet would be executed from top to bottom and left to right, just like reading a book. Here’s an example you might recognize from class: converting my dog’s weight in stone to his weight in pounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;weight_in_stone = 5.35&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;weight_in_pounds = weight_in_stone * 14&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;print(‘Tug weighs’, round(weight_in_pounds, 2), ‘pounds!’)&lt;/strong&gt;*&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flow of control is easy to follow and predictable. The lines are executed in this order:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Line 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Line 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Line 3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let’s turn this little bit of code into a function. Even though there’s not much going on with this calculation, it makes sense to turn it into a function, because:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It could easily be reused in lots of different contexts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It clearly takes one input (weight in stone) and computes a value (weight in pounds).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s a calculation we might need more than once in the same program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turning this calculation into a function alters the flow of control. Flow of control begins with &lt;em&gt;main&lt;/em&gt;, which is often called the “driver”, and should be the first place you look when trying to understand someone else’s code. Then, flow of control flows into a function when it is invoked. Flow of control goes back to the caller when a return statement is executed.  Let’s take another look at this example, as a more complete Python program:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-python &quot;&gt;
def stone_to_pounds(num_stone):
    num_pounds = num_stone * 14
    return num_pounds

def main():
    weight_in_stone = 5.35
    pounds = stone_to_pounds(weight_in_stone)
    print('Tug weighs', round(pounds, 2), 'pounds!')

main()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flow of control really begins at line 10 ( at &lt;u&gt;line 1&lt;/u&gt; and &lt;u&gt;line 5&lt;/u&gt;, we define functions but don’t execute them so the flow of control doesn’t go there yet). When we call the stone_to_pounds function, the flow of control goes up to line 1, and then returns to the caller at line 7. In all, here’s the flow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Line 10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Line 5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Line 6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Line 7 # invoke stone_to_pounds&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Line 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Line 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Line 3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Line 7 # flow of control returns to caller;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​       &lt;strong&gt;# variable&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;pounds&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;is initialized&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Line 8&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At line 3, the flow of control returns to the caller. Whatever value is stored in the variable &lt;em&gt;num_pounds&lt;/em&gt; is handed back to the caller. This value is used to initialize the variable &lt;em&gt;pounds&lt;/em&gt; in main.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Word on Testing (and more soon…)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We said above that one of the reasons for writing functions in the first place is so we can test our code programmatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll talk a lot more about testing and debugging in the next few weeks, but for now think of it this way: in the example above, we wrote a function to divide two numbers. Rather than calling the function and eyeballing the output, we can now call the function and write some code to verify that it worked as expected. Rather than hitting function+F5 over and over again to run the program with different inputs, we can use code to test our function many, many times without breaking a sweat. It’ll be great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Testing and Debugging&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We already know the most important part of testing and debugging: when something goes wrong, DON’T PANIC!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second most important part of this process is to find possible issues in our code early. Remember, most of the software you write will be used by people who aren’t you. We design and write a big, hopefully useful, piece of code, and hand it off to a group of users who want our software so they can accomplish something meaningful, creative, and substantive. And – I say this from experience – your users will act as if they are &lt;em&gt;trying&lt;/em&gt; to break your program. Your job is not to let them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Testing and debugging work together:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Testing&lt;/strong&gt; is the process of running a program (or parts of a program) to ascertain whether it works as intended.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Debugging&lt;/strong&gt; is the process of fixing a program that you already know does not work as intended.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good programmers write their programs in a way that makes them easier to test and debug. It’s not something to think about after you’ve written your program, but to think about before you begin writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll get some practice with testing in DS2000 by writing test suites. A test suite is a separate Python program, with its own &lt;em&gt;main&lt;/em&gt;, that repeatedly calls a function you’ve written to validate that it works correctly. A test suite will contain tests for multiple functions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 08:32:24 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/04/12/PythonLec2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/04/12/PythonLec2.html</guid>
        
        <category>Python</category>
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Seeing the unseeable</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-first-blackhole-picture-captured&quot;&gt;The first blackhole picture captured&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unveiling, before a crowd at the National Press Club in Washington D.C. and five other venues around the world, took place almost exactly a century after images of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/07/31/science/eclipse-einstein-general-relativity.html?module=inline&quot;&gt;stars askew in the heavens&lt;/a&gt; made Einstein famous and confirmed his theory of general relativity as the law of the cosmos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We live 26,000 light-years from the center of the Milky Way. That’s a rounding error by cosmological standards, but still — it’s far. When the light now reaching Earth from the galactic center first took flight, people were crossing the Bering Strait land bridge, hunting woolly mammoths along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In these dark days, it’s only fitting that the object of this pursuit is the darkest thing imaginable.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same logic also applies to ourselves, you may never know the limit of yourself, once you are settled down, it is hard and pricy for you to be go even one more step further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“To do this, we worked for over a decade,” Doeleman said, in a Washington, D.C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 08:32:24 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/04/10/Seeing-the-unseeable-black-hole-and-ego.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/04/10/Seeing-the-unseeable-black-hole-and-ego.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>996 viral:Chinese young engineers' Asilomar moment</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I haven’t really thought of living a life, Because I’m building something, and before I finish it, there won’t be anything else on my mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently there is a viral suddenly spread on github among Chinese computer engineers, on which they set up a project for protesting against the 996 work mode, which is a common practice in Internet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;996 vs. ICU&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/996.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;996 companies&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is 996?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A “996” work schedule refers to an unofficial work schedule (9 a.m. ~ 9 p.m., 6 days per week) that has been gaining in popularity. Serving a company that encourages the “996” work schedule usually means working for at least 60 hours per week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What can I do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Update this list with evidence to help every worker.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add this badge to your project to support 996.ICU.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;License your awesome projects with the 996ICU License.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add proposals to give advise and suggestion about the development of 996.ICU.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mapping the mechanism behind popular 996 work Demanding conditions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Struggle to have a life and work balance is due to the overtime working and strict conditions set on these young elites. They are deprived of their own life, thinking room, together with their happiness shared with family members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some digital media called 996 is a scandal for Chinese start-ups and giant technology empires, while I disagree with such criticism. The inside story is not fully presented by now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;IF THEY DO NOT PUT IN THE HOURS, THEY CAN EASILY JUST BE LAID OFF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://zqb.cyol.com/html/2019-04/02/nw.D110000zgqnb_20190402_1-02.htm&quot;&gt;被“996”工作制围困的年轻人：像是定好闹钟的机器&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 21:32:24 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/04/01/996-viral-Chinese-young-engineers-Asilomar-moment.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/04/01/996-viral-Chinese-young-engineers-Asilomar-moment.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
